Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music Records, 1996-2011
State University of New York at Buffalo, Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music Records, 1996-2011
Mus. Arc. 22
Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music
93 boxes
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music Records contain applications, including scores and audio/video recordings, submitted by individuals and organizations for grants from the Trust.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of Yvar Mikhashoff, 1996.
Accruals and Additions
Additions are expected biannually.
Biographical/Historical Note
Historical Note
The Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music was created in 1994 by the estate of the late American pianist Yvar Mikhashoff to support composers and performers of new music. The first year that the trust accepted applications was 1996. (The year reflects the year the applications were received, not the year that the award was given.)
Between 1996 and 2005, the competition guidelines were as such:
Funding Category I: Tuition Assistance for Student: Tuition assistance for students of composition or performance of New Music at appropriate educational institutes or with individual instructors in the United States or abroad.
Funding Category II: Fellowships, Grants and Awards: Fellowships, grants and awards for young professionals who will not have achieved their 30th birthday by the application deadline of December 1. Projects for career-advancing research or documentation (e.g. seminar/ workshop study, travel or recording) will be considered.
Funding Category III: Grants: Grants to music ensembles, presenting organizations, music festivals and recording companies which are devoted primarily to public presentations and/ or recording of New Music anywhere in the world.
There are no records for 2006 or 2007. The trust did not solicit applications in 2006. In 2007, the trust began using the year to reflect what year the awards were given as opposed to the year that the applications were received, therefore "skipping" 2007.
The trust modified the competition guidelines for the 2008 cycle. It became the Yvar Mikhashoff Pianist/Composer Commissioning Project. The goal of the competition is to encourage the composition and performance of new works for solo piano reflecting and continuing the legacy of the distinguished American pianist.
Biographical Note
Yvar Mikhashoff was born Ronald MacKay in Troy near Albany, New York in 1941. He began piano studies with Betty Weir and Stanley Hummel in Albany. At the Eastman School of Music in 1959, he first took a major in composition and cello, then changed to piano studies with Armand Basile. In the 1961 academic year, he studied piano at the Juilliard School in New York City. He also had a career as a ballroom dancer from 1962-1965.
In 1964 Mikhashoff entered the University of Houston for studies in piano with Albert Hirsh. He earned a B.M. in 1967 and continued with graduate study in composition with Elmer Schoettle and obtained his M.M. in 1968. It was during this period that MacKay adopted his grandfather's name, Mikhashoff.
Receiving a Fulbright scholarship, he studied the music of the French Impressionists with Nadia Boulanger. After his return to the United States, Mikhashoff entered the University of Texas at Austin as a doctoral candidate in composition and studied with Hunter Johnson, Kent Kennan, Janet McGaughey and Karl Korte. He earned a Doctor of Musical Arts degree with a major in composition and a minor in literature in August 1973 and founded the Cambiata Soloists ensemble. In the Fall of 1973 Mikhashoff was appointed Assistant Professor at the State University of New York at Buffalo. Based in Buffalo until his death in 1993, Mikhashoff had an international performing career which led him to promote new music and American music around the world.
Scope and Content Note
The Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music Records consist predominantly of the applications submitted by individuals and organizations. There is also some correspondence between the trust and applicants.
Funding Category I applications include the following:
Short Biography
Two letters of recommendation, to be sent separately by referees [Not available to the public]
Detailed proposal of study, including a budget
Academic transcripts if applying for tuition assistance at educational institutions [Removed]
Acceptance letter from proposed instructor if applying for private study
Recording, not to exceed 20 minutes in length, of representative 20th century solo repertoire from performers, or of representative compositions from composers.
Supporting materials were returned upon request when self-addressed stamped envelopes were included. Correspondence between applicant and trust may also be included, including follow up materials.
Funding Category II applications include the following:
Short Biography
Two letters of recommendation, to be sent separately by referees [Not available to the public]
Detailed proposal, including a budget
Recording, not to exceed 20 minutes in length, of representative 20th century solo repertoire from performers, or of representative compositions from composers. (scores were not sent unless requested)
Supporting materials were returned upon request when self-addressed stamped envelopes were included. Correspondence between applicant and trust may also be included, including follow up materials. Some include samples of press materials.
Funding Category III applications include the following:
History of the organization, including documentation of at least three years of existence as a not-for-profit organization [501©)(3)] or foreign equivalent [tax documentation removed]
Detailed proposal including budget
Representative printed programs, brochures and/or schedules. Organizations did not send recordings unless asked to do so
Recording, not to exceed 20 minutes in length, of representative 20th century repertoire- ensembles only [Added in 1996 guidelines]
Correspondence between applicant and trust may also be included, including follow up materials. Some include samples of press materials.
Beginning in 2008, the records consist of the applications submitted by pianists and composers for the Pianist/Composer Commissioning Project.
The pianist applications include the following:
A one-page biography
A list of solo piano pieces and concertos in the pianist's repertoire composed since 1950
A demonstration CD with performances by the pianist of a total of three pieces chosen from the repertoire list
Copies of three programs of past solo piano recitals
A CD or DVD documenting one of the above recital programs
A proposal for the premiere of the commissioned piece, including a letter of agreement with the presenting organization for a concert to take place between January 1 and September 1 of the following year
Correspondence between applicant and trust may also be included, including follow up materials. Some include samples of press materials.
The composer applications include the following:
A one-page biography
A representative list of works and performances
A signed letter of commitment to the project, stating his/her agreement to compose the piece in the time frame outlined and to attend the premiere
A CD of three recent compositions
A score of a solo piano work, if included on the recording
Correspondence between applicant and trust may also be included, including follow up materials. Some include samples of press materials.
Arrangement
A new series is created for every year, with subseries based on the application guidelines.
I. Administration
II. 1996
III. 1997
IV. 1998
V. 1999
VI. 2000
VII. 2001
VIII. 2002
IX. 2003
X. 2004
XI. 2005
XII. 2008
XIII. 2009
XIV. 2010
XV. 2011
Container List
- Administrative, 1994-2005, I.; Item A-001-A-002
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - Trust agreement, 1994 (Box 1, Item A-001)
  - Guidelines and submission information, Annual lists of applicants and awardees 1994-2009 (Box 1, Item A-002)
- 1996, II.; Item 1996-001-1996-184
  Arranged into five subseries:
  A. Individual award recipients
  B. Organization award recipients
  C. Individual applications
  D. Organization applications
  E. Audio recordings
  - Individual award recipients, 1996, A.; Item 1996-001-1996-006
    Arranged alphabetically by recipient name.
    - Bugallo, Helena (Box 1, Item 1996-001)
    - Cudd, Patti (Box 1, Item 1996-002)
    - Eckardt, Jason (Box 1, Item 1996-003)
    - Golove, Jonathan (Box 1, Item 1996-004)
    - Harris, John Mark (Box 1, Item 1996-005)
    - Wolfe, Lisa (Box 1, Item 1996-006)
  - Organization award recipients, 1996, B.; Item 1996-007-1996-014
    - Almeida Opera [Almeida Theatre] (Box 1, Item 1996-007)
    - California E.A.R. Unit (Musical group) (Box 1, Item 1996-008)
    - InterArts Chicago, Inc. (Musical group) (Box 1, Item 1996-009)
    - June in Buffalo (Box 1, Item 1996-010)
    - North / South Consonance (Musical group) (Box 1, Item 1996-011)
    - Relâche: The Ensemble for Contemporary Music (Box 1, Item 1996-012)
    - Tigertail Productions (Box 1, Item 1996-013)
    - Voices of Change (Musical group) (Box 1, Item 1996-014)
  - Individual applications, 1996, C.; Item 1996-015-1996-051
    Arranged alphabetically by applicant name.
    - Bahr, Jason (Box 2, Item 1996-015)
    - Bielawa, Lisa (Box 2, Item 1996-016)
    - Bryant, Steven (Box 2, Item 1996-017)
    - Carpenter, Keith (Box 2, Item 1996-018)
    - Daniels, Mathew (Box 2, Item 1996-019)
    - Fredrics, Howard (Box 2, Item 1996-020)
    - Fried, Joshua (Box 2, Item 1996-021)
    - Gardner, Alex (Box 2, Item 1996-022)
    - Griffin, Charles B. (Box 2, Item 1996-023)
    - Hammel, Elena (Box 2, Item 1996-024)
    - Hardy, David (Box 2, Item 1996-025)
    - Hersch, Michael N. (Box 2, Item 1996-026)
    - Huebner, Eric (Box 2, Item 1996-027)
    - Jalbert, Pierre (Box 2, Item 1996-028)
    - Johnson, Aaron (Box 2, Item 1996-029)
    - Kaplan, Amelia (Box 2, Item 1996-030)
    - Leisner, David (Box 2, Item 1996-031)
    - Lillios, Elainie (Box 2, Item 1996-032)
    - Livingston, Hugh (Box 2, Item 1996-033)
    - Mahoney, Shafer (Box 2, Item 1996-034)
    - Matsunuma, Koichi (Box 2, Item 1996-035)
    - McWain, Andrew Jackson (Box 2, Item 1996-036)
    - Moore, Keith (Box 2, Item 1996-037)
    - O'Donnell, Heather (Box 2, Item 1996-038)
    - Palmer, Juliet (Box 2, Item 1996-039)
    - Presler, Anna (Box 2, Item 1996-040)
    - Rohde, Kurt (Box 2, Item 1996-041)
    - Roland, Tomm (Box 2, Item 1996-042)
    - Rovan, Joseph W. (Box 2, Item 1996-043)
    - Rutkowski, Christopher (Box 2, Item 1996-044)
    - Ryan, William (Box 2, Item 1996-045)
    - Schneller, Oliver (Box 2, Item 1996-046)
    - Sharman, Rodney (Box 2, Item 1996-047)
    - Terry, Brett (Box 2, Item 1996-048)
    - Trueman, Dan (Box 2, Item 1996-049)
    - Van Hoy, Jeremy (Box 2, Item 1996-050)
    - Woltmann, Chris (Box 2, Item 1996-051)
  - Organization applications, 1996, D.; Item 1996-052-1996-147
    - Albany Symphony Orchestra [Dogs of Desire (Musical group)] (Box 3, Item 1996-052)
    - American Chamber Ensemble (Box 3, Item 1996-053)
    - American Chamber Opera Society (Box 3, Item 1996-054)
    - American Festival for the Arts (Box 3, Item 1996-055)
    - Arcana (Musical group) (Box 3, Item 1996-056)
    - Artemis and the Wild Things (Box 3, Item 1996-057)
    - Atlantic Center for the Arts (New Smyrna Beach, Fla. ) (Box 3, Item 1996-058)
    - Auros Group for New Music (Box 3, Item 1996-059)
    - Bachanalia Festival Orchestra (Box 3, Item 1996-060)
    - Bang on a Can All-Stars (Box 3, Item 1996-061)
    - Bargemusic (Box 3, Item 1996-062)
    - Boston Music Viva (Box 3, Item 1996-063)
    - Chamber Music Society of Baltimore (Box 3, Item 1996-064)
    - Cal Performances (Organization) (Box 3, Item 1996-065)
    - College of Notre Dame of Maryland (Box 3, Item 1996-066)
    - Colly Soleri Music Center at Arcosanti (Box 3, Item 1996-067)
    - Common Sense Composers Collective (Box 3, Item 1996-068)
    - Composers' Forum ( U.S. ) (Box 3, Item 1996-069)
    - Composers Recordings, Inc .. (Box 3, Item 1996-070)
    - Cornish College of the Arts ( Seattle, Wash. ) (Box 3, Item 1996-071)
    - Creative Music Productions, Inc. (Box 4, Item 1996-072)
    - Cygnus Ensemble (Box 4, Item 1996-073)
    - Debussy Trio (Box 4, Item 1996-074)
    - Dinosaur Annex Music Ensemble (Box 4, Item 1996-075)
    - District Curators (Box 4, Item 1996-076)
    - DiverseWorks Artspace (Box 4, Item 1996-077)
    - Downtown Music Productions (Box 4, Item 1996-078)
    - Earplay (Musical group) (Box 4, Item 1996-079)
    - Encompass Music Theatre (Box 4, Item 1996-080)
    - Ensemble 21 (Box 4, Item 1996-081)
    - Essential Music (Musical group) (Box 4, Item 1996-082)
    - Fabrica De Sons (Box 4, Item 1996-083)
    - Florida International University (Box 4, Item 1996-084)
    - Friends and Enemies of New Music (Box 4, Item 1996-085)
    - F.U.T. (Fyns Unget Tonekunstnerselskab / The Funen Society for Contemporary Music) (Box 4, Item 1996-086)
    - Golden Fleece Ltd., The Composers Chamber Theatre (Box 4, Item 1996-087)
    - Guild of Composers, Inc. (Box 4, Item 1996-088)
    - Greenwich Village Singers (Box 4, Item 1996-089)
    - Guild Trio (Box 4, Item 1996-090)
    - Harvest Works (Box 4, Item 1996-091)
    - House Foundation for the Arts/ Meredith Monk (Box 4, Item 1996-092)
    - Illinois Valley Orchestra Association (Box 4, Item 1996-093)
    - Jazz Composers Alliance (Box 5, Item 1996-094)
    - Korean Performing Arts Institute (Box 5, Item 1996-095)
    - Lewis-Clark State College (Box 5, Item 1996-096)
    - Little Rockies Arts Association (Box 5, Item 1996-097)
    - Los Angeles Contemporary Exhibition (Box 5, Item 1996-098)
    - Long Island Composers Alliance (Box 5, Item 1996-099)
    - Master Musicians Collective (Box 5, Item 1996-100)
    - MELA Foundation (Box 5, Item 1996-101)
    - Meridian Arts Ensemble (Box 5, Item 1996-102)
    - Merkin Concert Hall (Box 5, Item 1996-103)
    - Minnesota Contemporary Ensemble (Box 5, Item 1996-104)
    - Mishinna Productions (Box 5, Item 1996-105)
    - Mosaic (Musical group) (Box 5, Item 1996-106)
    - Musician's Accord (Musical group) (Box 5, Item 1996-107)
    - Music in Motion (Box 5, Item 1996-108)
    - Music Under Construction (Box 6, Item 1996-109)
    - Music Vistas, Inc. (Box 6, Item 1996-110)
    - Newband (Musical group) (Box 6, Item 1996-111)
    - New England Conservatory of Music (Box 6, Item 1996-112)
    - New Hampshire Symphony Orchestra (Box 6, Item 1996-113)
    - New Horizons Chamber Ensemble (Box 6, Item 1996-114)
    - New Music Consort, Inc. (Box 6, Item 1996-115)
    - New World Records (Box 6, Item 1996-116)
    - New World Records (Box 6, Item 1996-117)
    - New York Foundation for the Arts (Box 6, Item 1996-118)
    - New York Virtuoso Singers (Box 6, Item 1996-119)
    - Next Stage Company (Box 6, Item 1996-120)
    - Norfolk Chamber Music Festival/ Yale Summer School of Music (Box 6, Item 1996-121)
    - North American New Music Festival (Box 6, Item 1996-122)
    - Opus One (Musical group) (Box 6, Item 1996-123)
    - Orpheus Chamber Orchestra (Box 6, Item 1996-124)
    - Pittsburgh New Music Ensemble (Box 6, Item 1996-125)
    - Prism Quartet (Box 6, Item 1996-126)
    - Roulette (Organization) (Box 6, Item 1996-127)
    - Russian American Music Theatre (Box 6, Item 1996-128)
    - San Francisco Chamber Singers (Box 7, Item 1996-129)
    - San Francisco Contemporary Music Players (Box 7, Item 1996-130)
    - San Jose Chamber Orchestra (Box 7, Item 1996-131)
    - Society for New Music (Box 7, Item 1996-132)
    - Sound Directions, Inc. (Box 7, Item 1996-133)
    - Sound Foundation (Musical group) (Box 7, Item 1996-134)
    - Soundstreams Canada (Box 7, Item 1996-135)
    - South Florida Composers Alliance (Box 7, Item 1996-136)
    - Speculum Musicae (Musical group) (Box 7, Item 1996-137)
    - Speculum Musicae (Musical group) (Box 7, Item 1996-138)
    - Telectu (Box 7, Item 1996-139)
    - Thamyris (Musical group) (Box 7, Item 1996-140)
    - Theater Chamber Players (Box 7, Item 1996-141)
    - University of Cincinnati Foundation (Box 7, Item 1996-142)
    - University of Wisconsin (Box 7, Item 1996-143)
    - Washington Composers Forum (Box 7, Item 1996-144)
    - Washington Performing Arts Society (Box 7, Item 1996-145)
    - Wizard Music, Inc. (Box 7, Item 1996-146)
    - Women's Philharmonic (Box 7, Item 1996-147)
  - Audio recordings, 1996, E.; Item 1996-148-1996-184
    - Bahr, Jason (Box 8, Item 1996-148)
    - Bielawa, Lisa (Box 8, Item 1996-149)
    - Bryant, Steven (Box 8, Item 1996-150)
    - Cudd, Patti (Box 8, Item 1996-151)
    - Cudd, Patti (Box 8, Item 1996-152)
    - Daniels, Mathew (Box 8, Item 1996-153)
    - Eckardt, Jason (Box 8, Item 1996-154)
    - Fredrics, Howard (Box 8, Item 1996-155)
    - Fried, Joshua (Box 8, Item 1996-156)
    - Fried, Joshua (Box 8, Item 1996-157)
    - Golove, Jonathan (Box 8, Item 1996-158)
    - Griffin, Charles (Box 8, Item 1996-159)
    - Hammel, Elena (Box 8, Item 1996-160)
    - Harris, John (Box 8, Item 1996-161)
    - Huebner, Eric (Box 8, Item 1996-162)
    - Jalbert, Pierre (Box 8, Item 1996-163)
    - Johnson, Aaron (Box 8, Item 1996-164)
    - Kaplan, Amelia (Box 8, Item 1996-165)
    - Leisner, David (Box 9, Item 1996-166)
    - Lillios, Elainie (Box 9, Item 1996-167)
    - Livingston, Hugh (Box 9, Item 1996-168)
    - Love, Jason (Box 9, Item 1996-169)
    - Mahoney, Shafer (Box 9, Item 1996-170)
    - Matsunuma, Koichi (Box 9, Item 1996-171)
    - McWain, Andrew Jackson (Box 9, Item 1996-172)
    - O'Donnell, Heather (Box 9, Item 1996-173)
    - Palmer, Juliet (Box 9, Item 1996-174)
    - Presler, Anna (Box 9, Item 1996-175)
    - Rohde, Kurt (Box 9, Item 1996-176)
    - Roland, Tomm (Box 9, Item 1996-177)
    - Roran, Joseph (Box 9, Item 1996-178)
    - Rutkowski, Christopher (Box 9, Item 1996-179)
    - Schneller, Oliver (Box 9, Item 1996-180)
    - Terry, Brett (Box 9, Item 1996-181)
    - Trueman, Daniel (Box 9, Item 1996-182)
    - Van Hoy, Jeremy (Box 9, Item 1996-183)
    - Woltmann, Chris (Box 9, Item 1996-184)
- 1997, III.; Item 1997-001-1997-092
  - Individual award recipients, 1997, A.; Item 1997-001-1997-006
    - Brand, Eliav (Box 10, Item 1997-001)
    - Fortunato, Nick (Box 10, Item 1997-002)
    - Kasparov, Andrey (Box 10, Item 1997-003)
    - Morgensen, Rene (Box 10, Item 1997-004)
    - Sullivan, Taimur (Box 10, Item 1997-005)
    - Van Hoy, Jeremy (Box 10, Item 1997-006)
  - Organization award recipients, 1997, B.; Item 1997-007-1997-013
    - Auros Group for New Music (Box 10, Item 1997-007)
    - Composers Forum ( U.S. ) (Box 10, Item 1997-008)
    - Experimental Intermedia Foundation (Box 10, Item 1997-009)
    - New Music Consort, Inc. (Box 10, Item 1997-010)
    - San Francisco Contemporary Music Players (Box 10, Item 1997-011)
    - Syracuse Symphony Youth Orchestra (Box 10, Item 1997-012)
    - Thamyris (Musical group) (Box 10, Item 1997-013)
  - Individual applications, 1997, C.; Item 1997-014-1997-022
    - Acquisto, Daniel S. (Box 11, Item 1997-014)
    - Arakida, Tomoko (Box 11, Item 1997-015)
    - Elashvili, Anna (Box 11, Item 1997-016)
    - Fried, Joshua (Box 11, Item 1997-017)
    - Hadjipetkov, Dimitar (Box 11, Item 1997-018)
    - Jessen, Edward (Box 11, Item 1997-019)
    - Lillios, Elainie (Box 11, Item 1997-020)
    - Moore, Keith (Box 11, Item 1997-021)
    - Starrett, Scott (Box 11, Item 1997-022)
  - Organization applications, 1997, D.; Item 1997-023-1997-057
    - Albany Symphony Orchestra [Dogs of Desire (Musical group)] (Box 11, Item 1997-023)
    - Bang on a Can All-Stars (Box 11, Item 1997-024)
    - Boston Musica Viva (Box 11, Item 1997-025)
    - Cal Performances (Organization) (Box 11, Item 1997-026)
    - Capital Composers Alliance (Box 11, Item 1997-027)
    - Cassatt String Quartet (Box 11, Item 1997-028)
    - CEMI (Box 11, Item 1997-029)
    - Chamber Music Society of Baltimore (Box 11, Item 1997-030)
    - Contemporary Music Forum (Box 11, Item 1997-031)
    - Cygnus Ensemble (Box 11, Item 1997-032)
    - Debussy Trio (Box 11, Item 1997-033)
    - DiverseWorks Artspace (Box 11, Item 1997-034)
    - Downtown Music Productions. (Box 11, Item 1997-035)
    - Encompass Music Theatre (Box 12, Item 1997-036)
    - Ensemble 21 (Box 12, Item 1997-037)
    - Extension Works (Musical group) (Box 12, Item 1997-038)
    - Hallwalls (Museum) (Box 12, Item 1997-039)
    - House Foundation for the Arts/ Meredith Monk (Box 12, Item 1997-040)
    - I Cantori di New York (Box 12, Item 1997-041)
    - Kaila Flexer and Third Ear (Box 12, Item 1997-042)
    - Living Arts of Tulsa (Box 12, Item 1997-043)
    - Merkin Concert Hall (Box 12, Item 1997-044)
    - Monmouth Civic Chorus (Box 12, Item 1997-045)
    - Mosaic (Musical group) (Box 12, Item 1997-046)
    - Newband (Musical group) (Box 12, Item 1997-047)
    - New Century Chamber Orchestra (Box 12, Item 1997-048)
    - New England Philharmonic (Box 12, Item 1997-049)
    - New Langton Arts (Box 12, Item 1997-050)
    - New World Records (Box 12, Item 1997-051)
    - Norfolk Chamber Music Festival/ Yale Summer School of Music (Box 12, Item 1997-052)
    - Paul Dresher Ensemble (Box 12, Item 1997-053)
    - Roulette (Organization) (Box 12, Item 1997-054)
    - San Francisco Choral Artists (Box 12, Item 1997-055)
    - South Florida Composers Alliance (Box 12, Item 1997-056)
    - Washington Square Contemporary Music Society (Box 12, Item 1997-057)
  - Audio recordings, 1997, E.; Item 1997-058-1997-092
    Arranged in two alphabetical sequences: personal names then organizations.
    - Acquisto, Daniel (Box 13, Item 1997-058)
    - Arakida, Tomoko (Box 13, Item 1997-059)
    - Brand, Eliav (Box 13, Item 1997-060)
    - Elashvili, Anna (Box 13, Item 1997-061)
    - Fortunato, Nick (Box 13, Item 1997-062)
    - Hadjipetkov, Dimitar (Box 13, Item 1997-063)
    - Kasparov, Andrey (Box 13, Item 1997-064)
    - Kasparov, Andrey (Box 13, Item 1997-065)
    - Morgensen, Rene (Box 13, Item 1997-066)
    - Moore, Keith (Box 13, Item 1997-067)
    - Starrett, Scott (Box 13, Item 1997-068)
    - Sullivan, Taimur (Box 13, Item 1997-069)
    - Albany Symphony Orchestra [Dogs of Desire (Musical group)] (Box 13, Item 1997-070)
    - Auros Group for New Music (Box 13, Item 1997-071)
    - Boston Musica Viva (Box 13, Item 1997-072)
    - Cassatt String Quartet (Box 13, Item 1997-073)
    - Cassatt String Quartet (Box 13, Item 1997-074)
    - Cassatt String Quartet (Box 13, Item 1997-075)
    - Cygnus Ensemble (Box 14, Item 1997-076)
    - Encompass Music Theatre (Box 14, Item 1997-077)
    - Ensemble 21 (Box 14, Item 1997-078)
    - House Foundation for the Arts/ Meredith Monk (Box 14, Item 1997-079)
    - I Cantori di New York (Box 14, Item 1997-080)
    - Kaila Flexer and Third Ear (Box 14, Item 1997-081)
    - Monmouth Civic Chorus (Box 14, Item 1997-082)
    - Newband (Musical group) (Box 14, Item 1997-083)
    - New Century Chamber Orchestra (Box 14, Item 1997-084)
    - New Langton Arts (Box 14, Item 1997-085)
    - New Music Consort (Box 14, Item 1997-086)
    - New Music Consort (Box 14, Item 1997-087)
    - Paul Dresher Ensemble (Box 14, Item 1997-088)
    - San Francisco Contemporary Music Players (Box 14, Item 1997-089)
    - Syracuse Symphony Youth Orchestra (Box 14, Item 1997-090)
    - Thamyris (Musical group) (Box 14, Item 1997-091)
    - Washington Square Contemporary Music Society (Box 14, Item 1997-092)
- 1998, IV.; Item 1998-001-1998-071